<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>net.sourceforge.gMKVExtractGUI</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>Unlicense</project_license>
  <name>gMKVExtractGUI</name>
  <summary>A small GUI utility to use mkvinfo and mkvextract cli tools from MKVToolnix pack, in order to extract tracks, chapters and CUE sheets from mkv files.</summary>
  <description>
    <p>See https://forum.doom9.org/showthread.php?t=170249</p>
  </description>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://files.nils.moe/screenshots/net.sourceforge.gMKVExtractGUI/01.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <url type="homepage">https://forum.doom9.org/showthread.php?t=170249</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://sourceforge.net/p/gmkvextractgui/tickets/</url>
  <developer_name>gpower2</developer_name>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
  <releases>
    <release version="v2.11.1" date="2025-08-16">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>fix: Fix issue with Job manager when adding tracks that don't have CodecPrivate data, like PGS subs. thanks arestarh</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.11.0" date="2025-08-01">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>feat: Add tooltips and an option to disable/enable them. Closes #21 (#24)</li>
          <li>feat: Support checking/unchecking all Forced tracks per track type.</li>
          <li>feat: Add support for the Forced track property. Closes #20</li>
          <li>feat: Add option for overwriting existing files when extracting. This closes #18 (#19)</li>
          <li>feat(tags): Add output filename options for tags. Closes #12</li>
          <li>feat: Changed the output file extension for the OGM chapter type from "ogm.txt" to "txt" in the gMKVToolNix.MkvExtract namespace. Closes #4</li>
          <li>fix(linux): Fix some more possible Linux issues with P/Invoke</li>
          <li>fix(linux): correctly fix gRichTextBox issue in Linux</li>
          <li>fix(linux): Fix some issues in Linux by excluding paths with P/Invoke</li>
          <li>docs: Enhance README and add docs folder with a basic User Manual</li>
          <li>tests: Introduce Unit Tests and refactor part of the code for testability and performance (#11)</li>
          <li>perf: Improve context menu creation</li>
          <li>perf: Core refactor</li>
          <li>Huge refactor of parsing state, practically making parsing stateless</li>
          <li>Refactored the process output handling, by using List instead of StringBuilder to avoid splitting into individual line strings afterwards</li>
          <li>Removed file existence checks for batch requests to minimize the IO operations</li>
          <li>Various code optimizations in string operations</li>
          <li>Various code formatting improvements</li>
          <li>Refactor gMKVMerge, option handling and codec private data logic (#15)</li>
          <li>Refactor gMKVInfo, fix typos and improve parsing (#14)</li>
          <li>Refactor gMKVExtract and related components (#13)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.10.0" date="2025-06-18">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>fix(ui): Show "Extraction completed!" message in the segment info text box instead of the label status, to avoid visual clatter (thanks @dclxvplusone)</li>
          <li>feat(chapters): Add new PBF chapter type. It automatically transforms the default XML chapter type to the PBF chapter type. Comes with no guarantees, since documentation is basically non-existent</li>
          <li>Reorganize and refactor various parts of the code. Switch to using Newtonsoft.Json via Nuget and update to latest version</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.9.1" date="2025-05-31">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>fix(init): Revamped the init sequence for detecting the MKVToolnix path and added a new button to manually trigger the auto detect sequence</li>
          <li>fix(logs): Fix various logs in FrmMain2 and gMKVHelper</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.9.0" date="2025-05-26">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>fix(progress): Update the task bar progress bar value based on the total progress and not on the individual job progress</li>
          <li>fix(code): Switch to unboxed types and minor optimizations</li>
          <li>fix(gForm): Add the form handle in the remaining message boxes in gForm</li>
          <li>feat(dark): Implement Dark Mode in a new way with a bit of help from AI (thanks Jules!)</li>
          <li>fix(files): Fix file structure</li>
          <li>Create README.md</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.8.1" date="2025-05-24">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>fix(dark): Possible fix of a bug with ComboBox in dark mode (thanks vertigo220!)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.8.0" date="2025-01-05">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>
            Add support for Dark Mode
          </li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.7.0" date="2024-12-15">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Add explicit support for AV1 video codec</li>
          <li>Add support for appending input files via drag and drop (thanks vertigo220!)</li>
          <li>Make the success dialog popup appear as top most form across desktop (thanks vertigo220!)</li>
          <li>Fix the Abort buttons state before the success dialog pop up appears (thanks vertigo220!)</li>
          <li>Add new placeholder for directory separator in Options (thanks Liquid, oniiz86!)</li>
          <li>Add new Status Strip in Options form in order to make resize easier</li>
          <li>Add min size in the Options form to avoid minimizing it to size 1,1</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.4" date="2023-01-29">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>
            Minor code optimizations
          </li>
          <li>
            Add final Trim when generating the output filename (thanks tormento!)
          </li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.3" date="2022-09-24">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>
            Fix calculating delays from mkvinfo. (Thanks kedautinh12!)
          </li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.2" date="2022-04-09">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>
            Fix attachment filename for all cases. (Thanks mastrboy!)
          </li>
          <li>
            Improve track selection when filter value is an empty string
          </li>
          <li>
            Optimize algo to avoid unnecessary comparisons
          </li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.1" date="2022-03-05">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>
            Replace invalid file characters with underscore character ('_') from output filename
          </li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.0" date="2022-01-09">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>
            Add support for new element "Language IETF"
          </li>
          <li>
            Minor code optimizations/modernization
          </li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.5.2" date="2020-01-26">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>
            Fix issue in checking for an existing job when adding a new job
          </li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
